<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.8.7">Jekyll</generator><link href="/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2020-07-28T06:25:47+00:00</updated><id>/</id><title type="html">The Various Artists</title><subtitle>static site - booooom!</subtitle><entry><title type="html">Your website needs attention</title><link href="/2020-07-28-your-website-needs-attention/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Your website needs attention" /><published>2020-07-28T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2020-07-28T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>/your-website-needs-attention</id><content type="html" xml:base="/2020-07-28-your-website-needs-attention/">&lt;p&gt;A few short years we all assumed that the future was one in which a business could create a website, pay the hosting bill and generate leads (or sales) 24/7 for almost no cost.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That future didn’t eventuate.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Not even close.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Instead we have businesses struggling to comprehend an increasingly complex digital ecosystem and the larger than expected ongoing costs required to maintain a successful web presence.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Across a range of industries and clients we (&lt;a href=&quot;http://weareva.com.au/&quot;&gt;weareva.com.au&lt;/a&gt;) see that sites left unattended decline on all fronts and fail to deliver useful returns for their owners.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To understand how this happens I propose that there are several powerful forces at work that you have to keep up with as best you can.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The forces cross Aesthetic, Technical and Experiential bounds.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Aesthetic Forces -&lt;/strong&gt; This area is simply dealing with how your site looks. Time marches on and even a mint condition car from 1978 looks old compared to a new car. Humans are wired to somehow know what “new” looks like. A site that is 5 years old will look 5 years old and your customers spend plenty of time online looking at prettier sites and shiny new apps. How important this is varies from industry to industry but I don’t think anyone wants an old looking site.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Technical Forces -&lt;/strong&gt; These forces come in 2 main areas. The first are the changes required by “&lt;strong&gt;search algorithms&lt;/strong&gt;” to keep your site being found and indexed on search engines.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If having your site constantly ranking organically is important then this is an almost endless task. Constantly helping your users to find what they need by creating new content and refining existing content is an ongoing commitment. Using the data you see in Google Analytics takes the guess work away but there is simply no way to create quality content cheaply.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The other area of technical change is to the “&lt;strong&gt;code&lt;/strong&gt;” that makes your site run efficiently and safely.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Code on the server and in the browser (front end and back end) needs updates, patches and fixes to remain secure, fast and lay the groundwork for the kinds of experiences that users come to expect.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Example: IF your site was built before their was the ability to login via Facebook you need to add that functionality now as users do expect that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Experiential Forces -&lt;/strong&gt; Your users understand that your company isn’t Airbnb/Uber/Apple/Google or Facebook and they will tolerate your site not giving them the “user experience” that they get when they use those sites/apps. The downside is that they probably don’t give you as much leeway as you’d like. The bar of user experience is pushed ever higher by the biggest companies in the world and you at least have to try and stay in the game. Letting your site fall further and further behind via inaction will certainly paint your business in a poor light.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If this all sounds like a money grab from web designers/developers then I encourage you to look around. It is pretty obvious that the online and offline world aren’t that dissimilar.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Real Estate agents don’t drive old cars and/or wear old clothes.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Restaurants change menus and some of the decor at least a few times per year&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Teen fashion stores don’t play &lt;em&gt;So Fresh: The Hits of Spring 2000&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;A top level dept store doesn’t have staff in 5 year old uniforms.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Simply stated, your site will cost you time and money each and every year. As a guide I’d suggest that you allow 20-80% of your original build costs annually to keep your site moving forward and kicking goals for your business.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">A few short years we all assumed that the future was one in which a business could create a website, pay the hosting bill and generate leads (or sales) 24/7 for almost no cost.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">The case for the small agency team</title><link href="/2020-07-28-the-case-for-a-small-agency-team/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="The case for the small agency team " /><published>2020-07-28T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2020-07-28T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>/the-case-for-a-small-agency-team</id><content type="html" xml:base="/2020-07-28-the-case-for-a-small-agency-team/">&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;For most SME Digital marketing has not totally replaced all of your traditional marketing so now you have to do both.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Social media promised free access to your audience and now with your organic reach in single digits you are faced with paid social media and close to zero audience growth.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Your website was pitched as a 24/7 salesman working in your absence to generate leads (and even sales) but now you need endless content and/or updates to battle to any relevant position in Google rankings.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;You probably are considering if not already doing paid search and banners.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Your email database had a great open rate a year ago but now is funnelled into hidden folders inside your users inbox if not in the spam bucket.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Sending a newsletter on a constant basis is becoming a grind&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;We worked for a Sydney Based Driving School who fondly recalled that the ONLY thing he needed to do 20 years ago was pay for  Yellow Pages advertising. We scoff at Yellow Pages now thinking that we are so much more sophisticated but as a business owner myself I can understand his pining for simpler (and cheaper) times.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;## &lt;br /&gt;
Business marketing has never been more complicated or expensive!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Short of abandoning the bulk of these channels it isn’t going to get any easier.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you are a small business you can’t do it all and you can’t build a multi disciplined team to do it for you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Even if you are a larger organisation the chance of hiring an expert in each discipline - creative, marketing, copywriting, photography, video and web development is still a struggle&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can maybe hire yourself a gun in one area but other efforts will be below par or outsourced.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The’ jack of all trades’ may be ok but if your brand wants to stand out then mediocre marketing is not what you need.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-case-for-a-small-agency-team&quot;&gt;The case for a small agency team.&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;A team of experts all on the same page and likely under the one roof - or at least all at the end of a zoom call&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;One team to communicate with and one team to measure.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;A bunch of freelancers may give you access to individual experts but the cost of managing them all will be borne by you the client&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;A small team with little to no red tape will get far more done than an internal marketing resource who are probably in an unnecessary meeting right now&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;For less that the wages of one expert a small team like VA will kick big goals&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;To talk about specifics of outsourcing your marketing please use the contact form below&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">For most SME Digital marketing has not totally replaced all of your traditional marketing so now you have to do both. Social media promised free access to your audience and now with your organic reach in single digits you are faced with paid social media and close to zero audience growth. Your website was pitched as a 24/7 salesman working in your absence to generate leads (and even sales) but now you need endless content and/or updates to battle to any relevant position in Google rankings. You probably are considering if not already doing paid search and banners. Your email database had a great open rate a year ago but now is funnelled into hidden folders inside your users inbox if not in the spam bucket. Sending a newsletter on a constant basis is becoming a grind</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">In the beginning of the internet, there were only “static”​ sites.</title><link href="/2020-07-28-in-the-beginning-of-the-internet-there-were-only-static-sites/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="In the beginning of the internet, there were only &quot;static&quot;​ sites." /><published>2020-07-28T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2020-07-28T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>/in-the-beginning-of-the-internet-there-were-only-static-sites</id><content type="html" xml:base="/2020-07-28-in-the-beginning-of-the-internet-there-were-only-static-sites/">&lt;p&gt;These were handwritten HTML documents place on a web server so that internet users could access the content - the first one is still running here (&lt;a href=&quot;http://info.cern.ch/hypertext/WWW/TheProject.html&quot; title=&quot;http://info.cern.ch/hypertext/WWW/TheProject.html&quot;&gt;http://info.cern.ch/hypertext/WWW/TheProject.html&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once a website scaled to a decent size though these types of sites became increasingly difficult to maintain. (As an extreme thought exercise imagine changing the footer text on Amazon if every page was a standalone document !)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the early to mid 90’s a range of techniques were invented to allow websites to run scripts and leverage other server-side techniques to preprocess each page and display the output. This meant that instead of crafting each page as a separate document some level of automation was introduced to help manage ever-growing websites.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Dynamic database driven sites soon became the norm (and still the best way) to manage not just large sites but also any kind of online presence that needs regular updates or to display information tailored for each individual user (e-commerce, news sites, social media feed)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These sites, now powered by well know opensource CMS platforms like WordPress, Drupal and a plethora of proprietary systems like Squarespace, Sitecore etc, are common but also carry a sometimes lethal flaw for many operators. Sites powered by these platforms (opensource or proprietary) are under almost constant bot attack and require increasing levels of vigilance to ensure that the underlying database and server are not compromised. The database, often full of personal information, and a compromised web server capable of sending spam are usually the key pieces of the pie sought after in these attacks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;This is not a fear mongering article and we can confidently say that in the hands of a skilled operator or vendor who performs (or is diligent enough to automate) these tasks such attack vectors can be mitigated.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Out of the box, our friend the good old fashioned static website has almost none of the security issues noted above and in recent time advancements in the tools needed to manage them have now reached maturity. The new waves of static site builders automate the production of ALL the pages needed as a one-off task and then deploy these pages to the web server where users can access them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This means the security and speed of the good old fashion HTML sites of yesteryear with enough modern smarts to make updates a breeze. No database needed!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At VA we are throwing our hat in the ring for modern static sites deploying one last week (using Jekyll as the generator and Forestry.io as the “CMS”) for our client #&lt;a href=&quot;https://stratapp.ai/&quot;&gt;stratapp&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This site is a great example of a one that is easy to maintain, close to unhackable AND really really fast.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Achieving close too 100/100 for the desktop speed test and mid-high 90’s for the mobile experience (live data &lt;a href=&quot;https://developers.google.com/speed/pagespeed/insights/?url=stratapp.ai&amp;amp;tab=desktop&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;) you just can’t argue that for the right project this approach runs rings around a typical CMS build.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;VA is not about to throw out our top shelf Drupal and Wordpress chops as these 2 platforms are still among the best choices for mid to larger websites. That said we will be seriously pursuing this development stack for small to medium size websites that have little need for dynamic database driven content.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">These were handwritten HTML documents place on a web server so that internet users could access the content - the first one is still running here (http://info.cern.ch/hypertext/WWW/TheProject.html)</summary></entry></feed>