<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.8.7">Jekyll</generator><link href="/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2020-07-28T06:05:20+00:00</updated><id>/</id><title type="html">The Various Artists</title><subtitle>static site - booooom!</subtitle><entry><title type="html">The case for a small agency team</title><link href="/2020-07-28-the-case-for-a-small-agency-team/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="The case for a small agency team " /><published>2020-07-28T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2020-07-28T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>/the-case-for-a-small-agency-team</id><content type="html" xml:base="/2020-07-28-the-case-for-a-small-agency-team/">&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;For most SME Digital marketing has not totally replaced all of your traditional marketing so now you have to do both.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Social media promised free access to your audience and now with your organic reach in single digits you are faced with paid social media and close to zero audience growth.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Your website was pitched as a 24/7 salesman working in your absence to generate leads (and even sales) but now you need endless content and/or updates to battle to any relevant position in Google rankings.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;You probably are considering if not already doing paid search and banners.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Your email database had a great open rate a year ago but now is funnelled into hidden folders inside your users inbox if not in the spam bucket.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Sending a newsletter on a constant basis is becoming a grind&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We worked for a Sydney Based Driving School who fondly recalled that the ONLY thing he needed to do 20 years ago was pay for  Yellow Pages advertising. We scoff at Yellow Pages now thinking that we are so much more sophisticated but as a business owner myself I can understand his pining for simpler (and cheaper) times&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Business marketing has never been more complicated or expensive!&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Short of abandoning the bulk of these channels it isn’t going to get any easier.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you are a small business you can’t do it all and you can’t build a multi disciplined team to do it for you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Even if you are a larger organisation the chance of hiring an expert in each discipline - creative, marketing, copywriting, photography, video and web development is still a struggle&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can maybe hire yourself a gun in one area but other efforts will be below par or outsourced.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The’ jack of all trades’ may be ok but if your brand wants to stand out then mediocre marketing is not what you need&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;This article is the case for a small agency team.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;A team of experts all on the same page and likely under the one roof - or at least all at the end of a zoom call&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;One team to communicate with and one team to measure.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;A bunch of freelancers may give you access to individual experts but the cost of managing them all will be borne by you the client&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;A small team with little to no red tape will get far more done than an internal marketing resource who are probably in an unnecessary meeting right now&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;For less that the wages of one expert a small team like VA will kick big goals&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Happy to talk specifics if you are keen to outsource your marketing&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">For most SME Digital marketing has not totally replaced all of your traditional marketing so now you have to do both. Social media promised free access to your audience and now with your organic reach in single digits you are faced with paid social media and close to zero audience growth. Your website was pitched as a 24/7 salesman working in your absence to generate leads (and even sales) but now you need endless content and/or updates to battle to any relevant position in Google rankings. You probably are considering if not already doing paid search and banners. Your email database had a great open rate a year ago but now is funnelled into hidden folders inside your users inbox if not in the spam bucket. Sending a newsletter on a constant basis is becoming a grind</summary></entry></feed>