<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.8.7">Jekyll</generator><link href="/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2020-07-28T06:12:49+00:00</updated><id>/</id><title type="html">The Various Artists</title><subtitle>static site - booooom!</subtitle><entry><title type="html">The case for a small agency team</title><link href="/2020-07-28-the-case-for-a-small-agency-team/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="The case for a small agency team " /><published>2020-07-28T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2020-07-28T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>/the-case-for-a-small-agency-team</id><content type="html" xml:base="/2020-07-28-the-case-for-a-small-agency-team/">&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;For most SME Digital marketing has not totally replaced all of your traditional marketing so now you have to do both.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Social media promised free access to your audience and now with your organic reach in single digits you are faced with paid social media and close to zero audience growth.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Your website was pitched as a 24/7 salesman working in your absence to generate leads (and even sales) but now you need endless content and/or updates to battle to any relevant position in Google rankings.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;You probably are considering if not already doing paid search and banners.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Your email database had a great open rate a year ago but now is funnelled into hidden folders inside your users inbox if not in the spam bucket.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Sending a newsletter on a constant basis is becoming a grind&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">For most SME Digital marketing has not totally replaced all of your traditional marketing so now you have to do both. Social media promised free access to your audience and now with your organic reach in single digits you are faced with paid social media and close to zero audience growth. Your website was pitched as a 24/7 salesman working in your absence to generate leads (and even sales) but now you need endless content and/or updates to battle to any relevant position in Google rankings. You probably are considering if not already doing paid search and banners. Your email database had a great open rate a year ago but now is funnelled into hidden folders inside your users inbox if not in the spam bucket. Sending a newsletter on a constant basis is becoming a grind</summary></entry></feed>